Guide to the Baldwin Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Henry De Forest Baldwin (1862-1947), 1789-1947; Series VIII; 15.5 linear feet (37 boxes)
  - Student papers
    - Notes, undated (Box 177, Folder 1454-1455)
    - Scrapbook, 1882-1886 (Box 178, Folder 1456-1459)
    - Yale Literary Magazine, 1883-1884 (Box 178, Folder 1460)
  - Topical files
    - Argonne Association...- New York City Charter (Box 179, Folder 1461-1474)
    - New York City Charter - New York City mayoral campaign, 1898-1913 (Box 180, Folder 1475-1482)
    - New York City Police - New York Taxation, 1905-1930 (Box 181, Folder 1483-1492)
    - New York City taxation - Photos, 1885 (Box 182, Folder 1493-1501)
    - Photos: family - miscellanea (Box 183, Folder 1502-1513)
  - Miscellanea (Box 184, Folder 1514)
- William Hillhouse, 1757-1847; Series IX; 1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged in chronological order.
  - 1757-1804 (Box 185, Folder 1515-1524)
  - 1805-1814 (Box 186, Folder 1525-1534)
  - 1815-1847, undated (Box 187, Folder 1535-1547)
- Susan W. Baldwin, 1858-1897; Series X; 1 linear foot (2 boxes)
  - Notebooks, 1858-1859 (Box 188, Folder 1548)
  - Correspondence
    - 1865 Jun - 1875 May (Box 188, Folder 1549-1563)
    - 1875 Jun - 1897, n.d. (Box 189, Folder 1564-1576)
- Roger Sherman Baldwin, 1931-1949; Series XI; 0.5; (1 box)
  This series contains correspondence arranged chronologically under the heading "Fairfield (Ct.) State Hospital."
  - Connecticut bar certificate, 1893 (Box 212, Folder 8)
  - Fairfield (Ct.) State Hospital, 1931 May - 1949 May (Box 190, Folder 1577-1587)
- Other Family Members and Miscellenea, 1775-1915; Series XII; 5.5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  This series contains material organized under the names of individual family members. Material is arranged alphabetically by type under each family member. The materials grouped under the heading Miscellenea were perhaps collected by Simeon Eben Baldwin.
  - Atwater, Thomas
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 191, Folder 1588)
    - Financial papers, 1778-1815 (Box 191, Folder 1589-1591)
  - Baldwin, David, documents, 1820-1821 (Box 212, Folder 3)
  - Baldwin, Edward Law
    - Legal notebooks, 1843 (Box 191, Folder 1592)
    - Student notebooks, 1840-1842 (Box 191, Folder 1593)
    - Commission appointment signed by the governor of Connecticut and passports signed by Secretary of State James Buchanan, 1846-1848 (Box 212, Folder 3)
  - Baldwin, Elizabeth S. Burr (Box 191, Folder 1594)
  - Baldwin, Emily Perkins
    - Account books (Box 191, Folder 1595-1596)
    - Miscellanea (Box 191, Folder 1597)
  - Baldwin, George W.
    - Notebooks, 1880-1915 (Box 192, Folder 1598)
    - Scrapbook, [ca. 1846] (Box 192, Folder 1599)
  - Baldwin, Rebecca
    - Account books, 1852-1872 (Box 192, Folder 1600)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 192, Folder 1601)
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman (Box 192, Folder 1602)
  - Burr family
    - Burr, Josiah: bills and accounts, 1775-1796 (Box 193, Folder 1603-1607)
    - Burr, Josiah and Sturges and Baldwin, Simeon, 1784-1795, 1797 (Box 194, Folder 1608-1609)
    - Miscellanea, undated (Box 195, Folder 1610-1611)
  - Cerf, Sol. B.: notebook, undated (Box 195, Folder 1612)
  - Day, Thomas: account book, 1816-1818 (Box 195, Folder 1613)
  - Foster, Eleazor, [ca. 1800] (Box 195, Folder 1614)
  - Foster, Henrietta Perkins Baldwin, [ca. 1840s] (Box 195, Folder 1615)
  - Gifford, Ellen M.
    - Account books (Box 195, Folder 1616)
    - Estate records (Box 195, Folder 1617-1618)
    - Journal (Box 195, Folder 1619)
    - Miscellanea (Box 195, Folder 1620-1623)
  - Gifford and Marrett family, undated (Box 196, Folder 1624-1625)
  - Green (Thomas) and Sun, 1805-1809 (Box 196, Folder 1626)
  - Hillhouse, James, financial document, 1828 (Box 212, Folder 3)
  - Judson, David (Box 196, Folder 1627)
  - Marsh, Jonathan (Box 196, Folder 1628)
  - Perkins, Enoch, 1798 (Box 196, Folder 1629)
  - Schroeder, John Frederick: estate records, 1821-1858 (Box 197, Folder 1630)
    - Life insurance document, 1834 (Box 212, Folder 3)
  - Sherman, Martha, 1827-1829 (Box 197, Folder 1631)
  - Staples, Seth (Box 197, Folder 1632)
  - Wetmore and Sherman, 1785-1788 (Box 197, Folder 1633)
  - Whitney, Elizabeth (Box 197, Folder 1634)
  - Winchester - Mears family (Box 197, Folder 1635)
    - Baptism certificate, 1865 (Box 212, Folder 3)
  - Miscellanea (Box 197, Folder 1636)
  - Genealogy (Box 198, Folder 1637-1641)
  - Miscellaneous papers
    - Amity Society, 1781-1782 (Box 199, Folder 1642)
    - Bethany Society, 1780 (Box 199, Folder 1643)
    - East Haven, 1780 (Box 199, Folder 1644)
    - Fair Haven, 1781 (Box 199, Folder 1645)
    - First Society, 1780 (Box 199, Folder 1646)
    - Mount Carmel, 1782 (Box 199, Folder 1647)
    - New Haven, 1780 (Box 199, Folder 1648-1649)
    - North Haven, 1781 (Box 199, Folder 1650)
    - West Haven, 1782 (Box 199, Folder 1651)
    - White Haven, 1781 (Box 199, Folder 1652)
  - Hartford and New Haven Turnpike toll accounts, 1803; 1814-1815 (Box 199, Folder 1653-1654)
  - Derby Fishing Company records, 1806-1842 (Box 200, Folder 1655-1656)
  - Derby Fishing Company records, 1806-1842 (Box 201, Folder 1657-1661)
  - Account books
    - Merchant, 1772-1775 (Box 202, Folder 1662)
    - Ship chandler, 1794-1808 (Box 202, Folder 1663)
    - Miscellanea, 1773-1775 (Box 203, Folder 1664)
  - Property maps and homestead plans, largely in New Haven area, 1816 and undated (Box 211F)
  - Collected documents, 1584-1797 (Box 212, Folder 1)
    Includes the following documents: Elizabethan legal document (1584 Feb 26) with wax seal; Muster roll of Captain Gamaliel Painter's Company of Saddlers, Collar, Shoe, and Harness Makers in the Corps of Artisans (1778); Letter to Ezra Stiles from multiple writers, including William Rogers regarding the manumission of a slave named Dorcas residing in Jamaica (circa 1791-1792); ship insurance certificate (1793 Dec 20); and certificate of appointment of a notary public and foreign language translator in Philadelphia signed by Thomas Mifflin, Governor of Pennsylvania (1797 Jun 17), attached to a copy of a French decree regarding the abolition of slavery in the colonies (1794).
  - Collected documents, 1800-1902 (Box 212, Folder 2)
    Includes property and legal douments from New Haven and other Connecticut jurisdictions; Long Wharf (New Haven) and ship accounts; broadsides (including one relating to the Missouri Compromise); an issue of the Ulster County Gazette (New York) with articles on the death and burial of George Washington; Portuguese consular documents; Monson Academy list of students, teachers, and trustees; indentures and commissions from Massachusetts; U.S. patents for hanging lamps and casters; menu for a steamer excursion from Rock Island to St. Anthony's Falls; Memorial of George Wilkes for a National Railroad to the Pacific; broadside regarding Dr. George Bennett of New Haven; and several examples of Japanese watercolor and calligraphy.
  - Presidential documents, 1814-1834 (Box 212, Folder 4)
    Includes commissions and letters patent signed by James Madison, James Monroe, and Andrew Jackson.
- Photographs, undated; Series XIII; 3 linear feet (7 boxes)
  This series contains albums and loose photographs.
  - Albums (Box 204, Folder 1665-1668)
  - Albums (Box 205, Folder 1669-1672)
  - Albums (Box 206, Folder 1673-1674)
  - Albums (Box 207, Folder 1675-1676)
  - Albums (Box 208, Folder 1677)
  - Photographs and miscellanea (Box 209, Folder 1678-1690)
  - Photographs and miscellanea (Box 210, Folder 1691-1695)
- Additional materials
  Primarily correspondence that was discovered after the rest of the collection had been reprocessed.
  Arrangement
  Arranged by names of Baldwin family members.
  - Baldwin, Ebenezer (1790-1837), biography written after his death, Circa 1837 (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Baldwin, Simeon (1761-1851), military commission, 1826 (Box 213, Folder 2)
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman, correspondence, Circa 1847-1936 (Box 213, Folder 3)
    Correspondence to or from several Roger Sherman Baldwins: RSB (1793-1863), RSB (1826-1856), and RSB (1869-1956).
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman (1793-1863), letter from Seth Staples regarding the Amistad trial, 1840 January 21 (Box 213, Folder 4)
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman (1793-1863), letter from Horace Greeley, 1860 (Box 213, Folder 5)
  - Baldwin, Emily, correspondence from her husband Roger Sherman Baldwin (1793-1863), Circa 1820-1863 (Box 213, Folder 6)
  - Baldwin, Charles, printed ephemera, 1826-1827 (Box 213, Folder 7)
    Comprises a catalogue of the Librairie de Behr & Kahl (in French) and Outline of the System of Instruction for Amherst College.
  - Marven, John C., correspondence, war service documents, and photograph, Circa 1861-1865 (Box 213, Folder 8)
    - Additional war service documents, 1861-1866 (Box 212, Folder 10)
      Includes promotion certificate signed by President Andrew Johnson.
  - Baldwin, Simeon Eben (1840-1927), correspondence, 1873-1920 (Box 213, Folder 9-18)
  - Baldwin family, printed ephemera, legal documents, and correspondence, Circa 1820-circa 1880 (Box 213, Folder 19)
- Additional materials, 1784-1788; Accession 2016-M-0001
  This accession consists of seven handwritten letters, 1784-1788, from Jabez Colton (1746/1747-1819; Yale College 1775) to his brother-in-law Simeon Baldwin (Yale College 1781).
  - Correspondence, 1784-1788 (Box 1, Folder 1)